MONY SARY

La Cañada Flintridge, CA

Phone: (562) 607-9358 | Email: sary.mony@gmail.com Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mony-sary-08980b1aa/

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary
Portfolio: www.monysary.com

SUMMARY

Web Developer with skills in frontend and backend, pursuing a position in web/software development. Leveraging 6 years of experience working in biotech and clinical labs. Skills in R&D, project management, team management, and research. Known for calm demeanor and good work ethics. Ability to independently and quickly learn new concepts, while being proactive and maintaining deadlines.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Tailwind CSS, Handlebars.js,

React.js, Material UI

Backend: Node.js, Express.js, APIs, Jest, Bcrypt, Socket.io, Git

Database: MySQL, Sequelize.js, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, GraphQL, Apollo GraphQL

PROJECTS

Name: Pet Pals

GitHub: https://github.com/BryantTrinh/Pet-Pals-A-Social-Media-App-for-Pets

Link: https://hidden-headland-00556.herokuapp.com/

- Description: Social media platform for pet owners to connect and chat with each other about their pets and schedule play dates!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of home, feed, and chatbox components. Backend coding of instant messaging feature with messages saving into database.
- Tools: ReactJS, Material UI, Node.js, Apollo Server, MongoDB, GraphQL, Socket.io

Name: Bits Please Chat

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary/Bits-Please-Chat

Link: https://damp-river-11459.herokuapp.com/

- Description: An online instant messaging app where users communicate using only emojis!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Backend coding of instant messaging feature, and database setup for creating user information and logging in.
- Tools: Handlebars.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Socket.io

Name: The Weather Dashboard

GitHub: https://github.com/monysary/Weather-Dashboard/ **Link:** https://monysary.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

- Description: A weather app that allows users to search for current and future weather forecasts of cities, as well as save and delete the searches!
- Responsibilities: Frontend coding of user interface. Setting up API connection with public weather API and saving searches into localstorage.
- Tools: HTML, Bootstrap, Javascript, Third Party API

EXPERIENCE

Pangea Laboratory - Tustin, CA

2020 - Present

Independent Contracting Consultant - Oct 2022 to Present

- Review laboratory documents pertaining to operation, quality assurance, and assay development while maintaining compliance with regulatory standards.
- Providing consultation for DNA sequencing tests and laboratory operations.

Laboratory Manager - Jul 2020 to Oct 2022

- Managed two separate teams concurrently, all consisting of a total of 8 technicians, 2 Clinical Laboratory Scientists, and 1 Associate Scientist.
- Initiated and led team meetings to improve laboratory operation and quality to meet regulatory standards.
- Independently researched new technology, then purchased and deployed said technology for use in the laboratory.
- Created documentation, using regulatory approved schemes, for laboratory operations.
- Wrote code for methods used by automated liquid handling robots.
- In charge of implementing a new DNA sequencing test for use on patient samples while adhering to regulatory standards.
- Multitasked between different projects on top of managing the lab.
- Prepared and helped lead laboratory inspection from the College of American Pathologist.
- Worked in a team of 10 to build an entire COVID-19 testing department .

Zymo Research Corp - Irvine, CA

2018 - 2020

Senior Research Associate - Jan 2020 to Jul 2020

- Trained and managed 2 lab associates to perform a DNA sequencing assay.
- Created a small scale Laboratory Information Management System using Excel and Macros for the sequencing assay.
- Troubleshooted issues regarding the sequencing assay.

Research Associate - Jun 2018 to Jan 2020

- Maintained communication with scientists and researchers interested in performing DNA sequencing.
- Performed research and development on new reagents for operations, and deployed its use in production.
- Sequenced 1000+ DNA samples with very minimal mistakes.

EDUCATION

Boot Camp Certificate: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA Oct 2022 - Feb 2023

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap CSS, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Biological Sciences, B.S: University of California Irvine, Irvine, CA 2012 - 2016